The most daring escape!
P.O.W. The Escape is a action, war film directed by Gideon Amir.
Cooper leads a group of American P.O.W.s, battling their way
to freedom as Saigon falls to the Viet Cong.
Col. James Cooper, played by David Carradine.
Johnston, played by Steve James.
Capt. Vinh, played by Mako.
Sparks, played by Charles R. Floyd.
Adams, played by Phillip Brock.
Thomas, played by Daniel Demorest.
The Escape is a 1986 American war film directed by Gideon Amir and
starring David Carradine, Charles Grant, Mako and Steve James.
It is a loose re-imagining of the plot of Vera Cruz, transposing it
from the Second Franco-Mexican War to the Vietnam War.
In the story, a group of captive U.S.
soldiers forge a pact with the commander of their North Vietnamese camp to help him defect to the West
with his personal treasure, but the lure of quick gain soon tests their fragile alliance.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, helicopter,
bomb, special forces, machine gun.